《绿箭》《闪电侠》前情提要
Previously on "Arrow" And "Flash"...
布里·拉万  是个很聪明的机器人专家
Brie Larvan, a quite brilliant roboticist who once developed
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
曾经开发出农用的微型机器蜜蜂
miniature mechanical bees for military use.
巴里  我黑入了蜜蜂的频率系统
Barry, I hacked into the bees' frequency.
翻译   Z小花儿  SophiaSaaaga
■
我在控制它们
I'm controlling them.
布里已经被控制了
Brie's restrained.
这是可植入生物刺激素
It's an implantable biostimulant.
翻译  Silence 细小小  肉松
这个小玩意儿
This little piece of technology's
能让我再次走路
gonna help me walk again?
在将它植入你的脊椎之后  没错
After it's implanted in your spine, yes.
翻译  PiPi~  木浅薰  桃子西
我认为昆汀·兰斯的证词
I found Quentin Lance's testimony to be
十分具有说服力
particularly compelling.
基于此
On the strength of it,
校对  沫沫  Z小花儿  Michael  精校  陈小圈
达克先生收押不能保释
Mr. Darhk will be held without bail
且不能获释
or possibility of release.
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
每晚跟你一起在这里执行任务
It is, uh, too hard to be here with you
又不能跟你相爱太难了
every night and not be with you.
我不想放开你
I don't want to let you go.
特效&后期 咖啡Lee  总监 苹果果
但我们已经分手了
But I'm already gone.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
限制访问页面
布里·拉万
犯罪信息
谋杀
无假释
释放日期: 2067年8月12日
释放日期: 2016年3月29日
用电脑时间到了  金发妞
Computer time's up, blondie.
还没到
Don't think so.
法官同意我每周
The judge granted me a minimum
至少可以用半小时电脑
of 30 minutes per week.
我还有九十秒
I have 90 more seconds.
法官不在  我说了算
Well, the judge ain't here. I am.
你这么想上网
Let's see what you're so hot for
到底是想看什么
without Internet connection.
蜜蜂
Bees.
我喜欢蜜蜂
I like bees.
绿   箭
第四季  第十七集
西娅  你后脚滑出去了
Thea, your back foot's sliding out.
没有
No it's not!
你没看到我
Just because you can't see me
并不代表我就不在
doesn't mean I'm not there.
就算你看不见我
You got to sense my presence
也必须感觉到我在这
even when I'm not in your eyeline.
有什么建议给我吗
What advice would you give to me?
试试看
Humor me.
你累了
You're getting tired,
肩膀都松懈了
you're dropping your shoulder,
没有护住躯干
and you're opening yourself up.
你把每天的晨跑
So you took your morning run
从六英里减到多少了
from 6 miles to what?
两英里吗
Maybe two?
是啊  照顾一个小毛孩
Yeah. Well, taking care of a toddler's
就像跑马拉松一样
a marathon in itself.
好  可如果你的耐力打了折扣
Right, but when you sacrifice your endurance,
你在练习时会很快没了力气
you're losing steam too early in our sessions.
再来一次
Let's go again.
不要了
Ohh, pass.
我都不知道该怎么解释
I keep on running out of excuses
哪来这么多新伤了
for all my new bruises,
伤还是你造成的  而不是坏人
and they're from you, not bad guys.
咱们除掉了达克之后
The streets have gone quiet since we took
外面就安宁了
Darhk off the board.
他的组织可没消停
His organization hasn't been.
还没解决掉蜂巢
Hive is still out there.
对  等他们露头了  我们会搞定他们
Yeah, and when they rear their head, we'll take care of them,
可咱们得先庆祝胜利
but we have to celebrate our victories.
如果不庆祝
If we don't,
就会忘了我们为何而战
we forget what we're fighting for.
怎么了
What's wrong?
艾利克斯接到了鲁维·达克的
Alex has a new job interview
新工作面试
with Ruvé Darhk
什么
What?
她想在四月六日选举前
She's looking for a new chief of staff
找到新的幕僚长
before the April 6 election.
还是不明白
Still don't see
你为何不回去参选  奥利弗
why you just can't put yourself back in the race, Oliver.
选民们不喜欢反复无常的候选人
You know, voters, they hate flip-flopping,
而这会是相当大的反复
and that would be a pretty big one.
我不能让他替恶魔王子的妻子卖命
I can't let him work for the wife of the prince of darkness.
如果他有更好的选择呢
And what if he got a better offer?
你要参加市长竞选吗
Are you gonna run for mayor?
帕尔默科技  他们在招新的公关主任
Palmer Tech. They're hiring a new head of public relations.
我听某个人说的
I just heard that from someone.
劳蕾尔  她又不是伏地魔
Laurel, she's not Voldemort,
我没事
and I'm fine.
这主意不错
That's a good idea.
你该让艾利克斯和费莉西蒂谈谈
You should tell Alex to talk to Felicity.
怎么
What?
没事  只是...
Nothing. It's just--
没想到你竟然知道伏地魔是谁
It's shocking that you know who Voldemort is.
我又不是流行文化绝缘体
Well, I'm not immune to pop culture.
我也读过点《哈利波特》
I read a few of the "Harry Potter" books.
真的么  我还想和西娅打赌你只看了电影
Really? I was gonna bet Thea that you just saw the movies.
还拍成电影了
There were movies?
奎恩先生  我的手下在哪里
Mr. Queen, where are my men?
我不知道  瑞特
I don't know, Reiter.
他们是你的手下
They're your men.
我不会等着他们杀了我
I wasn't gonna wait around for them to kill me.
那维聂迪克托夫小姐在哪里
And what of Miss Venediktov?
她还在这里
She's still here.
别动
Don't move!
我的神像在哪里
Where's my idol?
不关你的事了
It's not your concern anymore.
就在附近  我能感觉到
It's nearby. I can feel it.
他们赋予的力量
The powers they bestowed
在衰减  但
are on the wane, but--
够了
Enough!
正如我所说
As I was saying,
魔力正在失效
the magics are losing their potency,
可还是够我
but I still have enough to
迅速干掉你们俩
make short work of the two of you.
每单位价格二十五万美元
A quarter of a million dollars per unit.
难以想象这么小的东西
It's hard to believe something so small
竟然要这么多钱
could cost so much money.
数字设备公司发布的
When digital equipment corporation released
首款虚拟地址扩展器要价七十万美元
the first VAX, it cost $700,000--
所以这已经很划算了
So you could think of this as a bargain.
不过我们不想发起一场电脑革命
Except we're not starting a computer revolution here.
我们是在尝试修复脊髓损伤
We're trying to repair spinal injuries.
最新估计  脊髓受损的人
The new estimate of spinal injuries
每年就有1.2万
per year are at 12,000 people.
除非每个都是百万富翁
Unless everyone's a billionaire,
否则重新站起来还是个奢侈品
walking again is a luxury item.
听起来像丹尼斯先生会说的话
Sounds like something Mr. Dennis would say.
他已经说了
He already has.
他召开了董事会
He's called a board meeting
讨论价格点后面
to discuss how many zeroes he can add
他能加多少零
to the end of that price point.
我能帮什么忙吗
Anything I can do to help you?
不能  感冒成这样你什么也干不了
No. You can't do anything with that cold.
回家  好好休息  喝点鸡汤
Go home, get some rest, get some chicken noodle soup.
你怎么跟我妈妈似的
You sound like my mother.
我相信如果你妈妈在这
And I'm sure if she was here
肯定会让你听我宝贝女儿的话
she'd tell you to listen to my favorite girl.
宝贝
Hi, honey!
好吧  但这只是因为我的感冒药
Fine, but only because my cold medication
开始让我眼前出现重影了
is starting to make me see double.
别走啊  别别
Help-- help me. Help.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
他以为我们是双胞胎呢
He thinks we look like twins.
他好像不是这么说的
I don't think that's what he said.
他就是这么说的
I think he did.
有什么事吗  妈妈
What can I help you with, mom?
我漂亮的宝贝女儿
Well, my beautiful baby girl,
我是来拯救你的
I am here to rescue you.
在那场
After the...
粉手之后[老妈拼错了]
b-r-e-a-c-k-u-p,
你需要点正常的社交活动
you could use some regular socialization,
所以我们一起吃顿午饭吧
so how about a leisurely lunch?
天呐  我真不知道哪个更糟
Oh, my God. I don't know what's worse--
是你拼出分手这个词
The fact that you just spelled out breakup
还是你竟然拼错了
or that you misspelled it.
-错了吗  -错了
- Huh? - Yeah.
没事  妈妈  我很好
No. Mom, I'm fine.
我还有很多工作要做
I have a lot of work to do.
不  不用吃很久的  宝贝
No. Just a quick one, swe--.
抱歉  我打扰到你们了吗
Sorry. Is this a bad time?
你们今天真是源源不绝啊
You people are like tribbles today.
怎么了  没出事吧
What's up? Everything OK with--
你问奥利弗吗
Oliver?
我本来是想问你们的夜班
I was gonna say your night job,
就是你们晚上的那份工作
you know, that thing that you do at night.
哦  没有  挺好的
Yeah, no. That--that's fine.
奥利也很好
Ollie is--is fine, too.
其实我来是因为  艾利克斯
It's actually about Alex.
他已经没为竞选工作了
Um, he's no longer working on the campaign,
所以我
so I was--
天呐  是丹尼斯先生
Oh, my God. It's Mr. Dennis.
我还得去参加董事会
I have a board meeting.
但是
You know what?
他是个混蛋  所以让他等着吧
He's a jerk. He can wait.
你要问我艾利克斯的什么事
What'd you want to ask me about Alex?
一般别人先请我吃顿饭
You know, usually, someone buys me dinner
然后我们才开始解手铐
before we start breaking out the cuffs.
我以为你只是失去了魔法
I thought you just lost your magic,
但看来人格魅力也没剩多少了
but your charm seems to be waning, as well.
你怎么进来的
How the hell did you get in here?
我曾是拉斯·厄尔·高福
Heh. I used to be Ra's Al Ghul.
这我知道  我不明白的是
This I know. What I'm less clear of
为什么我的人还没有开始救援我
is why my resources haven't been deployed to get me out of here.
我来就是向你解释此事的
Well, that's what I'm here to explain.
虽然我的刑期是无期  马尔科姆
Although my time in here might be limitless, Malcolm,
我的耐心就没那么多了
my patience isn't.
真可爱
That's cute.
如我所说  我联系了你的人
As I was saying, I've been in touch with your resources,
他们对你好像没什么
and they don't seem to have any particular
旧情了  达米恩
love left for you, Damien.
大概是因为你爱搞阴谋诡计
Something to do with hocus and pocus
而且生气的时候
and killing fellow members
还杀人吧
when you get miffed.
蜂巢没有放弃创世纪
HIVE is moving forward with Genesis
但放弃了你
but not with you.
他们喜欢你在里面  不会惹麻烦
They like you here out of trouble,
但他们还是由衷希望你的庭审
but they do wish you the best of luck
能有个好结果
with your trial.
别不好意思
Don't be embarrassed.
像你这么大年纪
Performance issues are common
不行很正常
for men of your age.
你真的能看到身后的情况啊
Wow. You really do have eyes in the back of your head.
你不是说有工作吗
I thought you had work to do.
我觉得工作不着急
I realized it could wait.
最近你对我们一直很严厉
You've been pushing us pretty hard,
我也知道为什么
and I know why.
奥利弗  你会想念费利西蒂是正常的
Oliver, it's OK to miss Felicity.
谢谢你的安慰
I--I appreciate what you're doing,
但是我觉得不该由你来
But I don't think that you're the--
在这个问题上开导你  为什么
Person to help you through it? Why?
就因为我们的过去吗
Because of what we used to have?
是
Yeah.
我觉得正因为我们的过去
I thought maybe it just gave me
才让我更能理解你
a little insight.
我是说  说老实话
Well, I mean, in fairness,
我们也确实是被我搞砸的  所以
I did wreck what we had, too, so...
我得为你说一句  当时
In your defense, you were missing
你确实是失踪而且被认定死亡五年之久
and presumed dead for 5 years,
但我指的不是这个
but that's not what I mean.
我知道你对爱情多么投入
I know how passionately you love
也知道失去爱时你多么受伤
and how much it hurts once that love goes away.
可是  经历这么多
You know, between...
梅林  斯莱德·威尔逊
Merlyn, Slade Wilson,
还有拉斯·厄尔·高福
and Ra's Al Ghul,
我以为我会更坚强些的
I thought that I'd be a little tougher than this by now.
这种痛苦完全不同
That's a different type of pain,
它愈合得更慢
and this takes longer to heal,
但我会陪着你
but I'm here for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没有迟到  菲尔
‭You're not late, Phil.
我们还在等斯莫克小姐
We're still waiting on Ms. Smoak.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
菲尔  菲尔
Phil? Phil?
菲尔
Phil!
我马上报警
I'm calling 911!
手机没信号
I can't get a signal!
请原谅我的小朋友们
You'll have to excuse my tiny friends.
它们有时会有些不乖
Their "Beehavior" can be appalling sometimes...
但这也是被逼无奈
But it's a necessary evil.
因为我需要引起你们的注意
You see, I needed your full attention.
你到底想要什么
What the hell do you want?
开门见山
Straight to the point.
我喜欢
I like that.
在可植入生物刺激素芯片的帮助下
Your CEO has miraculously recovered from paralysis
你们的总裁奇迹般地从瘫痪中康复了
thanks to an implantable biostimulant microchip.
给我一个
Hand one over,
我们就"蜂"拥而去
and I'll "Bee" on my way.
我们只有一个原型机
There's only one prototype.
就在费莉西蒂·斯莫克体内
The one ‭inside Felicity Smoak.
所以该怎么把我提上她的日程呢
So what's a girl got to do to get on her calendar?
如果你想的话我可以和艾利克斯谈谈
I can talk to Alex if you want,
但我不能保证给他一个他喜欢的工作
but I can't promise a job he'll be excited about.
还是让他远离那个
Probably best to keep him away
超级大坏蛋的老婆比较好
from a supervillain's wife.
你说的没错
Yep. You're right about that.
你们好啊
Hello out there.
怎么回事
What the hell?
我在找费莉西蒂·斯莫克
I'm looking for Felicity Smoak
如果我们能谈谈那个可植入生物芯片
"Beecause" it would be swell if we could chat
就再好不过了
about a certain implantable biochip.
我相信你的董事会会很感激的
I'm sure your board would really appreciate it.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
布里·拉万
Brie Larvan!
你认识这个怪人
You know this wackadoodle?
去年我跟她有过过节
I had a run-in with her last year.
如果布里·拉万是来找你的
If this Brie Barvan is coming for you,
我们得把你弄出去
we need to get you out of here.
不不不  我觉得她不知道我是谁
No, no, no. I don't think she knew who I was.
她要找的不是我
She's after something else.
她提到了什么可植入
She said something about an implant.
可植入芯片
A biostimulant microchip.
现在只有一个能用的原型机
There's only one working prototype.
-在哪呢  -在我的脊柱底部
- Where is it? - In the base of my spine.
所以说我们还是得
Which brings me back to
赶紧把你弄出去
we need to get you the hell out of here.
我们得把所有人都救出去
Well, we have to get everyone out of here!
我收不到信号
I can't even get a signal.
她干扰了所有的通讯
She's jammed all communications.
天呐
Oh, my God.
目击者称
Eyewitnesses report
帕尔默科技
突发新闻
蜂群围绕在帕尔默科技总部
the bees have been swarming the Palmer Tech Headquarters
已经持续了十分钟
for the past 10 minutes.
进出该建筑的所有通讯...
All communication in and out of the building--....
你看到这个了吗
Have you seen this?
我刚才还在那里
I was just there.
我走了就是因为费莉西蒂...
I'd still be there if Felicity hadn't--
天呐  费莉西蒂
Oh, my God. Felicity.
你已经烧到四十度了  你要去哪
You have a 104 fever. Where do you think you're going?
去找救兵
To get help!
警察肯定已经知道这件事了
I'm pretty sure the police already know about this.
我说的不是警察
I'm not talking about the police.
有消息称星城警局已派去一支紧急救援小组
We are hearing that SCPD has sent in an ESU squad.
费莉西蒂在那里
Felicity's in there.
西娅也在  我打电话了没人接
Thea, too. I tried calling but no answer.
蜂群袭击的时候
She must have already been inside
她肯定已经在里面了
by the time the swarm hit.
约翰来了
John's coming in.
这是蜂巢干的  对吧
This is HIVE, right?
这次蜂群袭击肯定不是巧合
There's no way that this bee attack is a coincidence.
我觉得不是蜂巢
I don't think it's HIVE,
而且我认为那些不是蜜蜂
and I don't think those are bees.
不  蜜蜂不会发出
No. Bees don't give off hundreds
数百种不同的无线电射频
of different kinds of radio frequencies.
蜜蜂机器人  棒极了
Robot bees. Terrific.
去年费莉西蒂帮巴里·艾伦
Ok. Last year, Felicity helped Barry Allen
抓到了这些蜜蜂的发明者  布里·拉文
take the bees' inventor-- Brie Larvan.
所以这是来报复的
So it's payback.
拉文真是会挑日子
Well, Larvan picked a hell of a day for it.
唐娜也在里面
Donna is in there, too.
-什么  -她去了费莉西蒂的办公室
- What? - She stopped by Felicity's office to,
想让她开心点
you know, cheer her up a little.
着装准备
Suit up.
警局派了一支紧急救援小组去
The department just tried sending in an ESU squad.
他们没办法穿越蜂群
They couldn't get through that swarm.
如果他们的防弹衣都扛不住
Now if their kevlar couldn't hold,
你怎么知道你们的就行
what makes you think that yours will?
我们必须试试
We have to try.
我马上就没有耐心了  费莉西蒂·斯莫克
I am running out of patience, Felicity Smoak.
在我开始除掉董事会成员之前
You have 10 minutes before I start voting
你还有十分钟
board members out.
顺便一提  我的雄蜂比正常蜜蜂
FYI, my drones pack a lot more "Ow"
叮起来疼多了
than your typical sting.
时间在流逝哦
Ticktock, ticktock.
我们得离开这里
OK. We need to get out of here.
但是蜜蜂在外面  西娅
But, Thea, the bees are out there.
对  而且它们迟早会进来的
Yeah, and sooner or later, they're gonna be in here.
从今往后  我只买平底鞋
OK. From now on, I'm buying flats.
总是碰上这种袭击
I mean, these assaults are weekly.
简直无语
It's ridiculous.
真是太有悖于时尚了
It's just so not conducive to high fashion.
它们马上就进来了
OK. Definitely sooner than later.
我们被困住了吗
We're trapped?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
并没有
Not exactly.
好吧  哦不  我绝对没有
OK. Oh, no. I definitely don't have
适合这种场合的鞋
the right shoes for that.
不不
Oh, no.
你好
Hello?
有人吗
Anybody here?
"有  我们在呢  柯蒂斯
"Yes, we are here, Curtis."
我们等不及想听听你如何
And we just can't wait to hear how you used
用我们给你的
the cell phone that we gave you
营救帕尔默博士的手机
to help us rescue Dr. Palmer
来追踪回我们的...
to track us back to our...
秘密基地
secret lair"!
我们不用干掉那些蜜蜂
So we don't need to take out the bees.
我们只用对付拉文就行了
We just need to take out Larvan.
对  但我们进不去的话也没用啊
Yeah. Well, it doesn't make much sense if we can't get inside.
我的天呀
Holy frak.
你是
You're the--
等等  你是
And wait-- you're--
等等  你  你是
Wait, wait, wait-- you're--you're--
先说清楚  如果我晕过去了
Just so you guys know, if-- if I pass out
那是因为我生病了
it's because I'm sick,
不是因为  你懂得
not because, you know.
现在随便谁都能进来了吗
So can anybody just walk in here?
你就是那个臭名昭著的达米恩·达克
So you're the infamous Damien Darhk.
我懂了  你们是我的粉丝  对吗
Oh, I get it. ‭You're big fans, aren't you?
你们要跟我合影吗
You want me to pose for a selfie?
在星城  你是个大人物
Back in Star City, you were a big deal.
但是在这里  只有他才是
In here, the only big deal is him.
别动粗  先生们
No, no, no, no, gentlemen.
看来我们一开始关系就不好
I think we're getting off on the wrong foot.
不过肯定有别的办法可以...
There must be some sort of way that we can have--
抱歉  我只是想知道
Heh. I'm sorry. I just got to know
嘴是你自己缝的吗
did you sew that in yourself,
还是有缝唇师帮你缝的
or do you have some kind of lip-sewing guy?
你之前是怎么对付她的
How did you deal with her in the first place?
老办法  黑入系统
The old-fashioned way-- hacking,
但是没有电脑我做不到
but I can't do that without a working computer.
好吧  至少我们只要等奥利
OK. Well, at least all we have to do is wait for Ollie
和其他人赶来
and the rest of them to get here.
我以为我退出了
Just when I thought I was out.
我以为我把这些事都放下了
I thought I'd left this all behind.
听到了吗
Do you hear that?
蜜蜂
Bee.
一大群蜜蜂  在通气孔里
Make that plural-- bees in the air vent.
快走  快跑
Go! Run!
柯蒂斯
Curtis.
太奇怪了
Oh, this is so weird.
我刚做了个梦  你在梦里是绿箭侠
I literally just had a dream where you were the Green Arrow.
等等  是真的吗
Wait. This is happening?
-你是绿箭侠  -是的
- You're the Green Arrow?! - Yeah.
我一直以为数据分析的尼尔·亚当斯才是
I could have sworn it was Neal Adams in data processing.
这里就是弓箭洞穴
And this is the Arrowcave.
天呐
Oh, my God.
其实我们叫做避难室  这里就是避难室
Actually, we call it the bunk-- it's the bunker,
随便吧
but yeah.
你是助理地检劳蕾尔·兰斯
You're Laurel Lance, the ADA.
我在电视上见过你
I-- I've seen you on TV before.
你是兰斯队长
Oh! And you're Captain Lance!
你是  抱歉
And you're-- oh, I'm sorry.
我知道我之前见过你
I know I've met before,
可我真想不起你的名字
but I can't really place your name right now.
柯蒂斯  那是约翰·狄格尔
Curtis, that's John Diggle.
我需要你集中一会注意力
I need you to focus for a second, please.
天呐  这地方真是不可思议
Oh, my God. This place is unbelievable.
你们肯定用了很大的电量
I mean, you guys must be drawing some crazy electricity.
你们是怎么避开电网的呢
How do you keep it off the grid?
这是尖端科研实验室的超级计算机
This is S.T.A.R. Labs' 5000 exostation.
都是什么配置格的
What are the specs on this?
柯蒂斯
Curtis!
集中注意力
Get it together.
现在我开始明白绿箭侠的事了
OK. Now I'm starting to see the whole Green Arrow thing,
而且身体也感觉好多了
and I'm actually starting to feel better, too.
那是因为我们给你输了液
That's because we gave you an IV
补充水分
to rehydrate you.
这应该能让你撑几个小时
It should keep you going for a few hours.
好吧  先别管这些
OK. Forget the how for a second.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我在新闻上看到了蜂巢  费利西蒂在那
I saw the Bee Hive on the news. Felicity's in there.
我们正准备开始营救任务
Yeah, we're just about to mount a rescue mission.
你们知道那是什么东西吗
Do you guys even know what that is?
那是机器蜂军队
That is an army of robotic bees.
这就是我现在的生活了
Yeah. That's my life now.
布里·拉万  显然她黑进了
Brie Larvan. Apparently, she hacked
监狱计算机网络
the prison computer network
提前释放了自己  聪明
and got herself an early release. Clever.
随便用吧
Feel free to use that, by the way.
你不能把这么精妙的机器放在我面前
I mean, you can't put me in front of this beautiful machine
却不让我一试身手
and expect me not to take it for a test drive.
看来费利西蒂保留了各种罪犯的档案
Looks like Felicity keeps files on various criminals.
幕后者是什么人
Who's the Dodger?
看来我们有个高个子的
Looks like we have ourselves a taller,
男版费利西蒂了
more dude-like version of Felicity.
我可以帮忙
And I can help.
看看这些蜜蜂  它们就是微型电脑
Now look. These bees, they're tiny computers, OK?
加上费利西蒂困在楼里
With Felicity trapped inside,
你们需要有人黑进它们的系统
you guys are gonna need someone to hack them,
但是我得小心蜜蜂
but I'll have to "Bee" careful.
现在说蜜蜂的双关语还不太合适吧
It's too soon for bee puns, right?
-就当是吧  -嗯
- Let's assume that it is. - Yeah.
柯蒂斯  你能让蜜蜂静止不动
Curtis, can you immobilize enough bees
想办法让我们进去吗
to give us a way in?
只有一个办法能知道
There's only one way to find out.
做吧
Do it.
你要我加入这个队伍吗
You want me on the team?!
你想我加入这个队伍吗
I mean, you want me on the team?
开始行动
Let's go.
你现在看到我的价值了吧  奎恩先生
You see now the value of my prize, Mr. Queen?
你对自己做了什么
What have you done to yourself?
所有的东西都有流淌着原始的能量
There are primordial energies that flow through all things.
而我现在可以控制它们
I now command them.
你疯了
You're insane.
这就取决于你如何看待疯狂  奎恩先生
Heh. Madness is a matter of perspective, Mr. Queen.
你的道德观让你的双眼看不到
Your morality blinds you from understanding
我所取得的成就
what I have achieved.
我看到了
No, I understand.
你以杀人来获取力量
You're killing people to gain power.
换做是你会怎么做
And what would you do about it?
告诉我  你把我的神像藏哪去了
Now tell me where you have hidden my idol,
我答应让你们死得痛快点
and I promise to kill you both quickly.
不必了
We'll pass.
有多少只蜜蜂
OK. How many are there?
尽力想点开心事吧
Just try to think happy thoughts.
是时候黑进蜜蜂系统了
OK. Now it's time to hack some bees.
看来这个键的功能是这样
OK. So that's what that button does.
费利西蒂
Felicity.
Felicity!
柯蒂斯
Curtis?
你怎么知道这只蜜蜂的名字
How do you know that bee's name?
黑进去了  我黑进...
I did it! I hacked the...
蜜蜂的系统了
bees!
你怎么...  你怎么会在那里
How did you-- what are you doing there?
就是啊  现在还觉得自己在做梦
I know, right? I am still pinching myself. Heh.
所有的蜜蜂都飞走了
All the bees are gone.
不用谢  绿箭侠正赶过去
You're welcome. The Green Arrow is on his way,
还有黑金丝雀和斯巴达
as well as Black Canary and Spartan.
简直帅呆了
How cool is this?
他们会在西侧设备入口跟你们会合
They'll meet you at the west utility entrance.
你们能去到那里吗  我有说过帅呆吗
Can you get there? ‭Did I mention how cool this is?
柯蒂斯  你解除蜜蜂了吗
Curtis, have you deactivated the bees?
没  我是说解除了
Negative. Uh, I mean, positive.
抱歉  太紧张了
Sorry. I'm nervous.
蜜蜂都已经解除了
The bees are down.
糟了  又激活了
Uh-oh. Oh, it's negative.
不  蜜蜂又飞回来了
Negative! The bees are back!
我被踢下线了
I--I got kicked out!
走  退回里面
Ok, ok, come on. Go back inside.
退回里面
Back inside.
到底他妈的发生了什么
What the hell happened?
不知道  我们失联了
We couldn't see. I lost the feed.
他被蜇了
He got stung.
对  他有一些被蛰的症状
Yeah. He's having some sort of reaction.
他不只被蜇了
He didn't just get stung.
蜜蜂在你体内
The bee's inside you.
弄死它
Well, cut it out!
你们这儿有麻醉药吗
Do you guys have anesthesia around here --...
-柯蒂斯  快动手  -我找不到它
- Curtis, just do it! - I can't find it.
雄蜂
好吧  真是难以置信  其实...
Ok. Actually--and this is hard to believe--
这下麻烦可大了
we have a bigger problem.
蜜蜂正在奥利弗体内自我复制
The bee is replicating itself inside Oliver.
那些鬼东西
What did that thing
把绿箭侠怎么了
do to the Green Arrow?
狠狠地蜇了他
Stung him badly.
他会没事的  他会回来的
He'll be ok, and he'll be back.
其他人也是
So will the others.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
他们被那个蜜蜂人
They just got their butts kicked
完爆了
by that--that-- that bee man.
所以我们才让西斯科取外号
This is why we leave the nicknames to Cisco.
什么
What?
内部梗
Inside joke.
我曾以为我们是朋友  斯莫克
I thought we were friends, Smoak,
我以为你会想通的
that you were gonna come through.
十分钟前  你还有十分钟
10 minutes ago, you had 10 minutes to go.
你没时间了  眼镜妹
You're out of time, glasses.
因为我们的蜜蜂被拦住了
"Beecause" we got interrupted,
我就再给你五分钟
I'm gonna give you an additional 5 minutes
然后我就把董事会成员一个个干掉
before I start taking your board members off the board.
你的未婚夫看起来很可爱
Oh, and your fiance looks awfully sweet.
抱歉  是前未婚夫
Sorry. Ex-fiance.
你不能自投罗网
Ok. You cannot turn yourself in.
不  她反正都会对大家下手
No. She'd kill everyone anyway.
想想  她在你的办公室里
To think, she's in your office.
你要消毒办公室了
You're gonna have to sanitize.
她在我的办公室里  首先  确实恶心
Yes. She's in my office, which is, "A," yes, gross,
但其次  说明董事会成员没和她在一起
but, "B," means she's not with the board members.
既然她提到了奥利弗
You know, since she brought up Oliver,
宝贝  你有和他谈过...
honey, have you spoken to him--
妈  妈  妈  我在想事情
Mom. Mom, mom, mom, I'm thinking!
抱歉  但你知道吗  宝贝
I'm sorry. You know what, honey?
我很好奇  我...
I'm curious, ok? I--
我有办法了
I have an idea.
没有用
It's not working!
在帕尔默科技时你就成功了
You did it while we were at Palmer Tech.
雄蜂进化了  之后又改写了
The drone has evolved and adapted since then.
这些鬼东西就像博格人
The damn things are like The Borg.
《星际迷航》里的反派  他们...
The--the bad guys in "Star Trek," which--
费利西蒂在这里就好了
I wish Felicity was here.
可她不在  柯蒂斯  现在只有你
Well, she's not, Curtis! You are!
你必须得想想办法  好吗
Now you have to be able to do something, ok?
当这些东西达到临界数量  就会...
When these things hit critical mass, there's--
就像《异形》里的约翰·赫特
It's gonna be like John Hurt in "Alien"!
抱歉  我紧张的时候就爱引用流行文化
Sorry. When I get nervous, I make pop culture references.
好吧  你无法弄死它
Ok. You can't hack it out.
那你能把它引出来吗  比如...
Can you lure it out like some kind of--
不敢相信我说出了这个
I can't believe I'm saying this--
比如数字蜂蜜之类的
some kind of digital honey or something?
不一定  但如果真是模仿蜜蜂制造出的
Not exactly, but if these are really modeled after bees, then...
它们会以单一频率来定位自己
they'll operate on a singular frequency to orientate themselves.
如果能干扰频率  就能分散它们
If we can disrupt it, then we can disperse the colony.
唯一的问题是我们得生成一段够高的频率
Only problem is that we need to generate a high enough frequency
来破坏网络  但前提是你们
to damage the network, but unless you guys have
手头有便携声波发射器  那么
a portable sonic projector handy, then--
怎么
What?
这项科技好赞
This technology's amazing.
它能读取你自己发出的声音
It reads your own vocal emissions
然后通过数字输出端将其处理为多声道
and then reprocesses it via digital output into a multichannel.
我们懂了  很赞
Yeah, we get it. It's badass,
但它怎么能帮我们救奥利弗
but how is this gonna help us save Oliver?
只要给他来一整首玛利亚·凯莉的歌
Just give him the full Mariah Carey,
它就能中断这些蜜蜂所操控的
and it should disrupt whatever connection
任何连接
the bees are operating on.
你确定没问题吗
You sure about this?
没时间确定了
Don't have time to be sure.
柯蒂斯  动手
Curtis, do it!
三  二  一
3, 2, 1.
好  酷  炫
That...was...awesome.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
我必将胜利  奎恩先生
My victory's inevitable, Mr. Queen.
想想看  所有的能量都来自
Just think. All of this power came
人的血肉躯体
from the life essence of one man.
想象一下  当许多生命
Imagine what I will become
为我献祭  我会变成什么
when dozens of lives are sacrificed in my name.
你会变成怪物
You'll become a monster.
不  是神
No. A god.
我来展示给你看
Let me show you.
不  我还要更多能量
No. I need more.
你找到他们了
You get them?
对  他们在柯蒂斯的办公室里
Yeah. They were in Curtis' office
就在你说的那个地方
right where you said they'd be.
我没打算双关的
Uh, no pun intended.
这就像那个
Whoa! So this is like that thing
就是那部
from that, uh--
朱蒂·福斯特的电影
that Jodie Foster movie!
对  《战栗空间》
Yeah. A Panic Room.
其实更像停止使用的"虎穴"
It's actually more like a lair, decommissioned,
但如果我们把董事会成员弄到那里
but if we can get the board members in there,
他们可以从秘密出口逃出
then they can escape through a secret exit.
秘密出口
Secret exit?
你不觉得你在十五分钟前
Um, don't you think you should have thought of that,
就该想到吗
like, I don't know, 15 minutes ago.
对不起  那时候我忙着逃生呢
Oh, I'm sorry. I was busy trying not to die,
而且你不停地唠唠叨叨
and you were talking, talking, talking.
你总是对我藏着掖着  宝贝
Well, you don't open up to me, hon.
我有时候得逼你说出心里话
I have to force your feelings out of you sometimes
就像剥开心果一样
like--like a pistachio.
好了  斯莫克  我们得走了  快来
Ok, Smoaks. We got to go. Come on.
费利西蒂
Felicity.
妈
Mom!
费利西蒂
I mean, Felicity! Aah!
好了  我们离开了
Ok. We're moving.
我知道  找个东西抓着
I know. Hold on to something.
-什么  为什么  -为什么
- What? Why? - Why?
这部电梯只停地下层
This elevator only stops at the sublevel,
但我们需要停在...
and we need it to stop at the--
会议室那层
conference room floor.
我们好像过站了
Um, I think we missed our stop.
没有  没错
Nope. This is right.
我刚说了  电梯不停这层
Like I said, the elevator doesn't stop at this level.
什么  亲爱的  我想这是一面水泥墙
What? Um, honey, I think this is a concrete wall.
没错  但我们有爆破装备
Yeah, and these are explosive devices.
事实上  这些是自动通信设备
Actually, they're autonomous communication devices.
我真希望柯蒂斯还没想到
I'm just really hoping that Curtis hasn't figured out
如何阻止它们爆炸
how to stop them from exploding yet.
小心
Careful.
天呐  会很大声吗
Oh, my god! Is it gonna be loud?
好了  谁想踏上秘密电梯之旅
Ok. Who wants to go on a secret elevator ride
去...安全屋
down to the, um, panic room?
对  安全屋
Yeah. The panic room.
是在躲避蜂群吗
Trying to escape the hive?
保护好他们
Keep them safe.
什么
Ha? What?!
我美丽的小蜜蜂们
Beautiful creatures my bees.
它们会听你的话
They obey you.
神经植入
Neural implants.
以前你是用老法子控制它们
You used to control them the old-fashioned way.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
侥幸猜中的吧  我猜
Lucky guess, I guess.
为什么要选蜜蜂呢
So why bees?
为什么不喜欢会飞的松鼠呢
Why not an obsession with flying squirrels?
松鼠每年的死亡率不会高达30%
Squirrels aren't dying off at a rate of 30% per year,
而且没人在乎
and nobody cares,
但是蜜蜂对生命很重要
but bees are essential to life.
生命都是相通的
We're all connected.
世界就是一个大蜂巢
The world is one giant honeycomb.
要不是你威胁要人命
That "Kumbaya" might have a little more credibility
你那一套可能还稍微可信点
if you weren't ‭threatening people's lives.
你是说像这样吗
What, you mean like this?
我快没耐心了
I am running out of patience,
你朋友也快不行了
and your friend is running out of time.
快给我那该死的...
Now give me the damn--
真是尴尬
That was embarrassing.
我的L4脊椎骨上有个肿瘤
I have a tumor on my L4 vertebrae.
那狡猾的小东西绕在我脊髓上
The tricky little guy's wrapped around my spinal cord.
想要切除它  只能做手术
The only way to cut it out involves a surgery
而手术会导致我
that will leave me paralyzed
腰部以下瘫痪
from the waist down.
这些蜜蜂并不能让一个残废下地行走
All the bees in the world couldn't get a cripple to walk,
但后来我听说了你的神奇芯片
and then I read about your miracle chip.
当然了  我买不起
Of course, I couldn't afford it.
你态度好一点  我可能会给你
Maybe if you asked nicely.
我要芯片的规格书
I want the microchip specs,
否则《我的女孩》里我最爱的片段就是你朋友的下场
or your friend relives my favorite scene from "My Girl."
亲爱的  人人都有悲情问题
Ok, honey. We all have a sad sob story,
但杀人解决不了任何事情
but killing people doesn't fix anything.
图纸在柯蒂斯·霍特实验室的远程硬盘里
The blueprints are on a remote hard drive in Curtis Holt's lab.
你是个聪明的女孩
You are a smart girl.
弹性纳米管  超声波马达
Elastic nanotubes, ultrasonic motors,
压电陶瓷元素
piezoceramic elements.
这蜜蜂体内一应俱全
I mean, this bee's got everything.
我体内的这只吗
That was inside me?
对  以及它体内的数千只微型幼虫
Well, that and thousands of its microscopic larvae.
别担心  过几天就会好了
Don't worry. Should pass in a few days.
迫不及待了
Can't wait.
唐娜和其他人安全撤离了
Donna and the others made it out.
西娅和费利西蒂呢
Thea and Felicity?
她们还在里面
They're still inside.
至少我们知道这玩意能阻止蜜蜂
Well, at least now we know this stops the bees.
真要这么简单就好了  但我们用过这招
I wish it was that simple, but now that we've played that card,
它们肯定已经适应了
they've undoubtedly adapted to it,
不过我们刚用超级英雄装置
but we just beat a group of robot bees
打败了一群机器蜜蜂
using a superhero doohickey,
如果这还不值得击掌庆祝
and if that's not high-five-worthy,
就没有值得庆祝的了
I don't know what is.
柯蒂斯  现在真不是击掌的时候
Curtis, now is not the time for high-fives.
抱歉  我...太激动了
Sorry. I--you know, I just got excited,
等他们来了  一定要庆祝胜利
and, you know, you got to celebrate the wins when they come.
什么
What?
西娅和费利西蒂还被困在帕尔默科技
Thea and Felicity are still trapped inside Palmer Tech
现在不知有多少蜜蜂在那
with who knows how many more bees.
-我们没有胜利  -奥利弗
- We're not winning. - Oliver.
如果你想留在这里
So if you're gonna be down here,
如果你想跟我们合作
if you're gonna be with us,
你就要完全明白
then you need to understand the totality
自己要面对的是什么
of what it is you're signing up for.
如果我们不好好尽职
If we do not do our jobs perfectly,
就会有人死去
then people die
而且不只是陌生人
and not just strangers
还有朋友  家人  爱人
but friends, family, and loved ones,
所以  请你每次说笑
so think about that every time you crack a joke
或轻视我们的工作时  都想想这一点
or make light of what it is that we do!
我能跟你说两句吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
你不如干脆找几只小猫小狗
Any puppies you want to kick while you're at it,
乱踢一通  再扔进河里泄愤好了
bags of kittens that you want to throw down the river?
他需要听听那些
He needed to hear that.
没人需要听那些  奥利弗
Nobody needs to hear that, Oliver.
我知道你难受  但你不能拿柯蒂斯出气
I know you're hurting, but you can't take it out on Curtis.
我没拿柯蒂斯出气
I'm not taking it out on Curtis.
我就想让他明白
I just need him to see.
明白什么
See what?
我们过的不是什么好日子
That this is not a good life.
我曾离开过这里
I walked away from it,
我感觉很快乐
and I was happy.
八年以来  那是我头一次
For the first time in 8 years,
觉得满足
I was content.
那为什么要回来
So why did you come back?
我回来是因为费利西蒂
I came back because of Felicity.
她让我相信我们可以胜任
She convinced me that we could do this job,
可以拯救这座城市  并且不用
that we could save this city and not
向黑暗屈服  但...
surrender to the darkness, but...
我...我觉得我们做不到
I don't--I don't think that we can.
你现在会这么说
You're only saying that right now
纯粹是因为你现在痛苦万分
because you're in 10 different kinds of pain,
但残酷的真相是  费利西蒂
but the harsh truth is that Felicity--
她跟你分手是因为你的选择
she broke up with you because of your choices,
因为你对她撒的谎
because of lies that you told,
是你  奥利弗  不是绿箭侠
You - Oliver, not the Green Arrow.
我知道
I know.
我能挽救一座城  但挽救不了我的感情
It just doesn't seem fair that I can save a city
感觉不太公平
and not save my relationship.
奥利弗  生活本来就不公平
Oliver, life's not fair,
不论是在星城还是常春藤镇  但你是对的
Whether you're in Star City or Ivy Town, but you're right.
你可以挽救这座城市  每晚都如此
You can save this city, you do it every night.
你是人们希望的灯塔
You're a beacon of hope to people.
我只是希望你能试着
I just wish that you would try and use
给自己一点希望
some of that hope for yourself.
你好  伙计们
Hi, fellas.
要知道我看到别人进来都会皱眉
You know, I usually frown upon walk-ins,
但有什么需要吗
but how can I help you?
这次没狱警来救你了  达克
No guards are coming to save you this time, Darhk.
我们已确认了
We made sure of it.
很好  那他只用杀你俩了
Good because then he only has to kill two of you.
我知道你们多半在问自己
I know you're probably asking yourself,
"刚刚发生了什么"
"Self, what the hell just happened?"
原来你们的朋友  也是我的新朋友
It turns out your friend, my new friend,
阿玛尔先生的弱点就是唯一在世的亲人
Mr. Amar has a soft spot for his only surviving relative,
他奶奶还在市政局纪念厅
a grandmother in Monument Point.
语气和蔼打几通电话
It is amazing what people will tell you
人们就会告诉你好多事情
with a few phone calls and a kind voice.
好吧  他们死了吗  他们死了吗
Anyway--are they dead? Are they dead?
我本来还准备了一番精彩的言辞
No! I had this wonderful speech about how I was gonna kill
关于你没杀他们  我就杀你奶奶
your grandmother had you not killed them.
算了  继续做其他事吧
Never mind. On to other matters.
你现在可以致电你的组织
You may now call your organization
把另一条信息传递出去
and have that other message delivered.
我以为我们黑不进去了
I thought we were locked out.
我们得看看我有没有手生
Well, we're gonna have to see if I haven't lost my touch.
我还得看看我妈妈
Then I have to see if my mom
还有董事会成员成功脱险了没有
and the board members made it to safety.
你真不应该给布里想要的东西
You really should not have given Brie what she wanted.
我受不了人们身处险境
I am sick of people being put in vulnerable positions.
好吧  但现在什么都阻止不了她
Yeah. Well, now there's nothing stopping her
让那些蜜蜂回来蛰我们了
from bringing those bee things back on us.
至少我们  团队  你的团队有时间了
Well, at the very least, it buys us--the team-- your team time.
奥利不会有事的
Ollie's gonna be fine.
他总能逢凶化吉
He always is.
但不幸的是  对奥利弗来说
Well, unfortunately, in Oliver's case,
"他总能逢凶化吉"这预测并不准确
"He always is" isn't an accurate predictive metric.
抱歉  我受够担惊受怕
Sorry. I'm just sick of worrying,
受够暴力了
I'm sick of the violence.
我也是  好吗  我当然也是
Yeah. So am I, ok? Of course I am,
但我们得忍受
but we put up with it.
我们得撑下去
We push past it
因为我们做的事情很重要  是吧
because what we do is important, ok?
我们得成为希望的灯塔
We have to be the beacon of hope.
其他人不是
Nobody else is.
你们才是希望的灯塔
You're the beacon of hope.
我退出团队是因为我受不了和奥利弗合作
I quit the team because I couldn't stand to work with Oliver,
但我现在退出了
but--but now that I'm out,
我能以不同的视角看待生活
I look at life from a different perspective.
看看你身边
I mean, look around you.
西娅  我们在演《虎胆龙威之蜜蜂危机》
Thea, we're in a "Die Hard" movie with bees.
也许我会变得伟大  也许不会
Maybe I'm meant for great things, maybe I'm not,
无论怎样  都不该是这样
but whatever it is, it's not this.
抱歉  我不会回去
I'm sorry. I'm not coming back.
柯蒂斯
Curtis.
我开始明白
You know, I'm beginning to see
你和费利西蒂分手的原因
why you and Felicity didn't work out.
我多半活该
I probably deserve that.
我很想拥抱庆祝  学习消遣
Look. I'm all for hugs and learning,
但如你所说  还有危险
but like you said, there's still danger.
没错
Yeah.
而且你很可怕
And you are a very scary man.
蜜蜂有突破了吗
Any luck with the bees?
柯蒂斯正在努力
Curtis is doing his best.
谢谢  劳蕾尔  我已经能够
Thanks, Laurel. Now that I've been able
真正检测蜜蜂
to actually examine the bee,
我已经破解了他们的升级协议
I've deciphered their upgrade protocol.
他们下次改写时  我就能上传病毒
Next time they adapt, I can upload a virus
病毒会散布整个蜂巢
that will disperse into the entire Hive.
就像《独立日》[1996]里一样  对吧
Like what they did in "Independence Day," right?
怎么  我看电影很奇怪吗
What, I can't watch movies, too?
计划是什么
So what's the plan?
我给一支箭装上了计算机病毒箭头
I rigged an arrow with a computer virus payload.
射向蜜蜂女王的小兵附近
Shoot it near one of "Bee" Arthur's minions,
病毒会传向剩下的蜂群中
The virus will transmit to the rest of the colony,
就完事了
and we're done.
太棒了
That's nice work.
成功之后再称赞我吧
Wait until it works before you congratulate me.
我进去了  意思是我出来了
I'm in! I mean, I'm out.
意思是我有网络了
I mean, I have internet.
妈妈和董事会成员都安全了
Mom and the board members, they're ok.
那我们呢
What about us?
我在想办法控制
I'm working on overriding the bees,
在外面守卫大楼的蜂群
the ones that are outside guarding the building.
别费事了
Don't bother.
这些蓝图很有用
These blueprints will be useful.
谢谢
Thanks for those.
你拿到了蓝图
You have what you want,
你自己建去
so go build it yourself.
你们理解错了
I think we're confused.
为了拿到图纸  我得溜进
To get the schematics, I had to tip-toe
帕尔默科技的计算机网络
through Palmer Tech's computer network,
我看到了一些非常熟悉的代码
and I saw some very familiar computer code.
你永远不会忘记送你进监狱的黑客
You never forget the hacker who sent you to prison.
你好
Hi.
-这边安全  -至少没有蜜蜂的踪迹
- We're clear. - At least there's no signs of the bees.
跑
Go!
看来你的绿朋友没忘记你
Looks like your green friend didn't forget about you.
永远不会忘记
Never will.
你受伤了吗
Hey. Are you hurt?
我没事
I'm ok.
小心你身后
Hey! Behind you!
好了
There you go.
绿箭队  虽然我不是成员  捏捏我
Team Arrow, which I am now a member of--pinch me--
我需要几分钟攻破最新的防火墙
I need a few more minutes to hack this latest firewall.
蜜蜂改写了
The bees adapted.
我以为你射得很准
I thought you were a better shot.
好吧  加油  加油  加油
All right. Come on. Come on, come on, come on, come on.
-搞定了  -干得漂亮
- Gotcha! - Nice!
别担心  我不会告诉别人你叫出了声
Don't worry. I won't tell anyone you screamed.
对了
Oh, right!
谢谢
Thank you.
你永远都不必感谢我
You never, never have to thank me.
如果我无法走路  你也别想活命
If I can't walk, you can't live.
执行命令
上传完成
我应该先杀掉谁呢
Who should I kill first,
你呢  还是你
"A" Or "Bee"?
猜猜谁又重新掌控了局面
Guess who's back in control.
我是柯蒂斯  我怕你们还没听出我的声音
It's me Curtis in case you guys don't recognize my voice yet.
不  不
No, no!
成功解决"蜜蜂婊"
Lay down, "Bee-yotch"!
话太狠了
Too on the nose?
那只蜜蜂活过来了
The bee came alive,
让我们有点手足无措
And, well, things got a little out of hand,
不过别担心  它现在完蛋了
but don't worry -- it's dead now.
你干得很棒  柯蒂斯
You did good, Curtis,
很抱歉我之前对你不是很友好
and I'm--I'm sorry if I made you feel differently.
谢谢  绿箭侠  你介意我称你为绿箭侠吗
Thanks, G.A. Heh. Do you mind if I call you G.A.?
好吧  我以后还是叫你奥利弗吧
All right. Yeah. I'll just stick to Oliver then.
或者奎恩先生
Or Mr. Queen.
拉万怎么办  她会出什么事吗
What about larvan? What's gonna happen to her?
她正在星城总院
She's at Starling General,
因为体内的蜜蜂毒素超量
overdosed on toxins from the bee
她现在处于昏迷状态
and is in some sort of a coma.
更重要的是  她无法胁迫
More importantly, she's no longer holding
一群无辜的人质了
a dozen innocent hostages.
真是又让人欣慰  又骇人听闻
That's both comforting and horrifying at the same time.
没错  欢迎来到我们的世界
Yeah. Welcome to our world.
一切还好吗
Is everything all right?
是的  你知道的  我大概应该直接回家
Yeah. You know, I should probably just head home.
知道了你的  你懂得  你的真实身份
You know, learning that you're, you know, you
还有那群杀人蜜蜂  以及她陷入昏迷的消息
and the murderous bees and this coma news,
我得好好消化一下
it's just a lot to digest,
而且你们给我输液的药效也快没了
plus that IV you gave me is starting to wear off.
好吧  这里永远欢迎你  柯蒂斯
Well, you are always welcome here, Curtis.
下次别搞出
Just keep the property damage
这么大的破坏就行
to a minimum next time.
好
OK.
-出口在哪边  -就在那里
- What's the exit? - Right there.
好的
Oh, yeah.
你这番道歉很赞
Nice apology.
好吧  我只是想成为一座希望的灯塔
Well, I'm just trying to be a beacon of hope
像你所说的那样  给我自己
and, like you said, save a little bit
也留一点希望
of the hope for myself.
泰安娜
Taiana.
没事了  没事了
All right. All right.
天啊  拜托  拜托
Jeez. Come on, come on.
谢天谢地  泰安娜  醒醒
Oh, thank God. Taiana, wake up.
-嘿  -奥利弗
- Hey. - Oliver.
没事了  你还好吗
It's OK. You're OK.
-不  -没事了
- No. - It's all right.
瑞特  他不见了
Reiter-- he's gone!
他肯定在隧道里找他的神像
He must be in the tunnels searching for his idol.
我们不能让他找到它
We can't let him find it.
如果他正在隧道里找那尊神像
If he's in the tunnels searching for his idol,
这就意味着他没去牢里
that means he's not going to the prison.
这对我们来说是一个拯救你那些朋友的机会
This is our chance to save your friends.
那瑞特的手下呢
And what of Reiter's men?
他们还守在那里
They're still up there.
所以我们首先得解决他们所有人
That's why we're gonna kill all of them first.
我觉得现在热一下汤还不晚
I don't suppose it's too late to reheat that soup.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
你像疯了一样冲出家
You bolted out of here like a crazy person,
就像那种超级英雄要去拯救世界一样
like some kind of a superhero off to save the day.
我当时傻傻地幻想着
I was chasing some silly fantasy that
我能帮到警察
I could help the police.
极其恐怖  惊心动魄  也很危险
It was scary and thrilling and dangerous
我刚才提到"恐怖"这两个字了吗
and did I mention scary?
关键是  我所经历的一切
The point is -- is that I saw enough
让我明白了这才是我的归属
to know that this is where I belong--
在家跟你待在一起
at home with you.
所以不会再玩失踪了
So no more disappearing acts?
我保证
I promise.
我去给你盛点汤来
Let's get you some of that soup.
太好了
Terrific.
或许我应该在这里烧点驱虫香什么的
Maybe I should burn some incense in here or something.
是的  没准是个好主意
Yeah. That's probably a very good idea.
提醒我再也不要穿黑色和黄色的衣服
Remind me to never wear black and yellow ever again.
等等  你妈妈去哪里了
Wait. Where'd your mom go?
兰斯队长开车送她回家了
Captain Lance drove her home.
是的  碰到这种事我根本没法理解
Yeah. That is something I'll never be able to wrap my brain around.
感觉还蛮可爱
Eh, it's kind of cute.
你不想念这些吗
Don't you miss this?
我是说  我知道你说过你想要
I mean, I know you said that you wanted
远离这一切
to get away from it all,
但是你能做到吗
But how could you?
什么意思
What do you mean?
这些  让人惊心动魄的战斗
This. The-- the thrill of this, the rush.
我是说  今晚我们刚刚拿下了"蜜蜂婊"
I mean, we just took down a bad "Bee-yotch" tonight.
没有什么比这种感觉更好
It doesn't get any better than this.
我一点也不喜欢这种感觉  从没喜欢过
I was never in it for that, not ever.
我想要改变
I wanna make a difference.
成为你们所说的希望的灯塔
Be a part of that beacon of hope you speak of.
那就回来吧
So come back.
重新归队
Rejoin the team.
我想我找到了其它办法
I think I figured out another way.
其实是那个疯狂的蜜蜂女
It was actually that insane Bee Lady
给了我这种想法  很讽刺吧
who gave me the idea, ironically...
我想重振公司
to remake this company
通过那项能让我再次走路的技术
to use the technology that helped me walk again
造福人类
to make people's lives better,
让帕尔默科技成为希望的灯塔
to make Palmer Tech into the beacon of hope.
我们在蜂巢里的那位共同的朋友已经放弃了
Our mutual friends in HIVE have abandoned
我们另一位共同的朋友达克先生
our other mutual friend Mr. Darhk,
但是他来找我了
but he reached out to me,
跟我说起了你
told me about you.
他说你是他最后的王牌
He said you were his ace in the hole.
你想让我这么称呼你吗
Is that what you'd like me to call you,
或者你更喜欢被称做狄格尔先生
or do you prefer Mr. Diggle?